Guide to the Maurice Chester Bond papers, 1912-1980.
Bond, Maurice Chester papers, 1912-1980
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Maurice Chester Bond papers, 1912-1980.
21-24-248
Maurice Chester Bond, 1897-
8.7 cubic ft.
Reports, notes, journals, photograph album, mimeographed material, correspondence, memoranda, minutes, office calendars, desk and field notes, travel accounts, diaries, logs of trips, and other papers.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Reports; mimeographed and printed material from Agricultural Economics Extension files on subjects such as cooperatives, farm management, and marketing; articles and speeches on extension work; notes, journals, photograph album, mimeographed material, correspondence, memoranda, and minutes of various conferences, workshops, and committees; reports of the Los Baños Project in the Philippines (1963); office calendars, desk and field notes, travel accounts, and diaries; logs of trips to Germany, England, and Mexico; papers relating to Epsilon Sigma Phi, an honorary extension fraternity; and correspondence, notes, and other records pertaining to local organizations including the Ithaca Cooperative Consumers' Society Inc. and First Congregational Church of Ithaca (New York).
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Professor of marketing.
Maurice C. Bond (Cornell University Ph.D. 1928) taught marketing and was Director of Extension, Cornell University.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Reports; mimeographed and printed material from Agricultural Economics Extension files on subjects such as cooperatives, farm management, and marketing; articles and speeches on extension work; notes, journals, photograph album, mimeographed material, correspondence, memoranda, and minutes of various conferences, workshops, and committees; reports of the Los Baños Project in the Philippines (1963); color slides of the Cornell-University of the Philippines ICA project (1956-67); office calendars, desk and field notes, travel accounts, and diaries; logs of trips to Germany, England, and Mexico; papers relating to Epsilon Sigma Phi, an honorary extension fraternity; and correspondence, notes, and other records pertaining to local organizations including the Ithaca Cooperative Consumers' Society Inc. and First Congregational Church of Ithaca (New York).
SUBJECTS
Names:
Bond, M. C.1897-; Cornell University.Cooperative Extension.; Epsilon Sigma Phi.; First Congregational Church of Ithaca.; Ithaca Cooperative Consumers' Society.
Subjects:
Agricultural extension work.; Cooperative societies.; Farm management.; Farm produce--Marketing.; College teachers--New York (State)--Ithaca.; Voyages and travels.
Places:
Great Britain--Description and travel.; Germany--Description and travel.; Mexico--Description and travel.; Los Baños (Philippines)
Form and Genre Terms:
Field notes.; Photographs.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Alphabetical files
  - Account books, 1933-1942 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Account books, 1931-1935 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Advertising, 1948-1950 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - AGFU, 1948-1965 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - National Workshop on Agricultural Marketing, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Agricultural Society, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - American Institute of Cooperation, 1934-1935 (Box 1, Folder 7-10)
  - Articles - Extension staff and others, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Auctions, 1938-1943 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Banking and Currency Committee, 1937-1946 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - New York State Bankers Association, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Bibliography of Agriculture, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Bureau of Agricultural Economics, 1941-1947 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Central New York Regional Marketing Authority - manager's (Don D. Ward) report, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Commission merchants, 1926-1942 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Connecticut, 1938-1943 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Connecticut, Maine, Nebraska, 1930-1949 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Constitution - New York State, 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - C - miscellaneous, 1936-1954 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Consumer co-ops, 1928-1951 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Co-op Consumers Society, 1945-1971 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Ithaca Cooperative Consumers' Society, Inc., Director's Handbook, 1945-1947 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Co-op Food Store, 1942-1945 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Co-op Food Store - minutes of meeting, 1942-1946 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Costs - enterprise costs, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Farm Credit Administration - news releases, 1938-1943 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Credit - farm debt adjustment, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Dairy Barn Management Manual, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Cooperatives, 1938, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - C - miscellaneous, 1931, 1937-1959 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Report of the Visiting Professor and Extension Consultant, U.P.-Cornell Graduate Education Program, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - NYS College of Agriculture - history, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - NYS College of Agriculture - history, 1952-1954 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - NYS College of Agriculture, 1930-1951 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - NYS College of Agriculture, 1939-1953 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Agricultural Economics Extension - Plan of Work, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Agricultural Economics Extension - Plan of Work, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Annual Extension Conferences, 1928-1947 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - ECOP - Extension Committee on Organizations & Policy, 1958-1961 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Economic aspects of advertising and promotion, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Marketing Sub-committee of ECOP, Wash., D.C., 1956 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Marketing Sub-committee of ECOP, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Marketing Sub-committee of ECOP, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Marketing Sub-committee of ECOP - Task Force, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Marketing - Extension, 1954-1958 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - National Marketing Committee, 1957-1958 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - National Marketing Committee, 1956-1957 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - National Marketing Committee, 1955-1957 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - National Subcommittee on Marketing, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Marketing Committee - land grant meeting, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - National Workshop on Agricultural Marketing, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - MIC Regional Training Conference, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Marketing - Chicago, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - M - retailer education, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - National Subcommittee on Marketing, ECOP, Montana, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Food Marketing Extension - Upstate Training Schools, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Extension facts, 1959-1961 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Home Ec Specialists Handbook, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Extension, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Extension, 1937-1950 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Extension - cars - cost of operations, 1936-1944 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Extension - circulars, 1929, 1932 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Extension work with retailers, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Lecture notes, 1929-1953 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Extension articles, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - 4-H, 1955-1956 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Farm Bureau, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - NY Farm Bureau, 1956-1957 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Food Marketing Information, 1955-1958 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Food Marketing Information, 1953-1955 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - National marketing agreement - ice cream, 1933 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - International Conference on Agricultural Economics, 1951-1961 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Statistics (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Soil conservation, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - "Be Water Wise", 1954 (Box 2, Folder 36)
- Series II. Church and civic organizations
  - First Congregational Church
    - Church, 1957-1959 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Congregational-Agricultural Committee, 1956-1958 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - By-laws and constitution, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - New church, 1952-1961 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Church publicity, 1928-1931 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Church, 1928-1934 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Trustees minutes (not originals); letter by Rev. George and four quick meetings of trustees, 1925 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - Church organizations (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - Financial state re: loan, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - New church - Finance Committee - minutes and plans, 1952-1958 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Church, 1957-1950 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Church trustees, 1951-1953 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Church, 1950-1959 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Church, 1954-1956 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - New church, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Lists - members and friends, 1957-1960 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Church, 1956-1961 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - New church - miscellaneous, 1960-1961 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - New church - Finance Committee, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Church, 1957-1958 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - New pastor, 1958-1959 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Finances, 1955-1961 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Building fund brochure, canvass and publicity, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - New church - Finance Committee - correspondence and conference notes, 1957-1968 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Fraternities
    - Epsilon Sigma Phi, 1937-1962 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Epsilon Sigma Phi Annual Meeting, 1961-1962 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Epsilon Sigma Phi, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Epsilon Sigma Phi, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Epsilon Sigma Phi, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Phi Kappa Phi (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Phi Mu Delta (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Sigma Xi (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Rotary
    - Rotary Club, 1971-1972 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Rotary District 717 Conference (photos), 1971 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Rotary, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Ithaca rotary (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Rotary Club (Box 3, Folder 29)
- Series III. Articles, conference notes, talks
  - Articles - GLF, 1945-1950 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Articles, 1939 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Articles, 1937, 1938 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Articles, 1938-1959 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Articles, 1930-1937 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Articles, 1929-1940 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Conferences, 1959-1961 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Conferences, 1959-1960 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Conferences, 1958-1959 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Conference notes, 1953-1957 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Conference notes, 1959-1962 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Schedule, 1954-1961 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - "America's Future" Farm Broadcast, 1951-1952 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Talk material, 1960-1961 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Talk material, 1955-1960 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Talks, 1960-1961 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Talks, 1956-1960 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Talks, 1960-1962 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Talks, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Talks, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Talks, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Talks, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Talks, 1954 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Talks, 1955 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Textbook revision, 1951-1954 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - John Wiley and Sons, correspondence (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Series IV. Trips
  - European trip notes, 1934 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, et al. re: first trip re: review of Cornell contract with University of Philippines College of Agriculture, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Reports - Philippines and other, 1959-1965 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Reference facts, 1963-1964 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Extension Committee minutes, 1963-1964 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Terminal reports - College of Agriculture, U.P., 1961-1962 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Report - U.P. College of Agriculture alumni opinion survey, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Invitational Field Day, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Talks, 1963-1964 (Box 4, Folder 24-27)
  - Inauguration of Dr. Carlos P. Romolo (U.P.), 1963 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Inauguration of Pilar Hidalgo Lim (Centro Escolar U.) (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Letter from Major Max Myers, Philippines, 1945 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Fertilizer - Its Importance in the Development of Philippine Agriculture, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Philippines, 1962-1964 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - FHD and Extension U.P.C.A., 1965 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - FHD and Extension U.P.C.A., 1964-1965 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Batangas field trip - diversified farming, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - P.I. Extension, 1956-1957 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - P.I. trip, 1956-1957 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - P.I. Ag. Economics, 1956-1957 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Puerto Rico (summary in facts and figures), 1956 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - UPCA Monthly Bulletin, 1956-1957 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - UPCA Report on the visiting prof. and Ext. consultant, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Passport - visa - customs, 1959-1962 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Misc. correspondence UP - Visiting Prof. Bond, 1962-1964 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Peterson-Bond letters, etc. re: Philippine project - Extension and graduate education, 1962-1964 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Barnett, Dr. Milton E. - Council on Economic and Cultural Affairs - Philippines, 1962-1964 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - U.P. Cornell Grad. Ed. and Training (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Umali, Dean D. (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - C.E.C.A. with on Economics and Cultural Affairs, 1962-1964 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Notes, 1962-1964 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Notes from diaries, typed, 1962-1963 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Family expenses, 1923-1953 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Reimbursed travel, 1935-1953 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Case studies of farm families, Laguna Province, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Two publications re: agriculture in Los Banos, 1956, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - The Bulletin, Christian Inst. for Ethnic Studies in Asia, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Durfee Report - Philippines, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Philippines, 1962-1966 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Diary notes - P.I., 1962-1963 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Bond Report - U.P.C.A., 1964 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Philippines misc. (Box 5, Folder 30-33)
  - UPCA faculty talks on teaching review, 1964-1965 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Philippines misc. (Box 6, Folder 1-4)
  - Philippine travel to USA, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Travel misc. (Box 6, Folder 6-8)
  - Diary - So. American trip, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Maine and Killington, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Postcards - Peru (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Travel misc. (Box 6, Folder 12-13)
  - Philippine misc. (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Diary and notes - P.I., 1962-1963 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Philippine Extension (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Philippine trip, 1963 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Europe trip, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Travel misc. (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Travel notes and literature - Japan, 1963 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Taiwan, 1962 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Mexican trip, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Mexico trip (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Mexico trip postcards (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Travel misc. (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Some notes in Puerto Rico (album/scrapbook), 1937 (Box 6, Folder 26)
- Series V. Volumes
  - Photograph album - European trip (Box 7)
  - Schedule of Farmers' Institute, 1914-1929 (Box 7)
  - Sta. Maria-Mabitac First Report Field Study, 1963 (Box 7)
  - Sta. Maria-Mabitac Quarterly Report, 1963 (Box 7)
  - 12 notesbooks - Philippine trip notes, 1962-1964 (Box 7)
  - Diaries (30) plus misc., 1912-1940 (Box 8)
  - Diaries (48) notes, 1940-1949 (Box 9)
  - Diaries (35) field notes, 1950-1959 (Box 10)
  - Diaries (15) notes, 1950-1959 (Box 11)
  - Diaries (33), 1960-1975 (Box 12)
- Series VI. Personal papers
  - Expense accounts, 1954-1955 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Expense accounts, 1956-1957 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Expense accounts, 1958 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Expense accounts, 1959 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Expense accounts, 1960 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Expense accounts, 1961 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Certificates, awards (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Trip report - Albany, 1959 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Rotary Award, 1980 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Trip to Mexico (bound notes), 1949 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Mexican trip (carbon notes), 1949 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Trip reports, 1941-1942 (Box 14, Folder 1-4)
  - M.C. Bond - retirement letters, 1962 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Retirement (clippings), 19 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Thetford Academy, 1955-1961 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - University of Vermont - notes, 1955-1960 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Insurance, retirement, and compensation, 1943-1954 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - 150th anniversary of the birth of Ezra Cornell, 1956 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Appointment - Director of Extension (bound volume), 1954 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Reminiscences of Flora Holway Bond, 1962 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Six 12" 78 rpm phonograph records: WGY Farm Forum, Aug. 26, 1955, Dec. 13, 1957, M.C. Bond talking on Separation of Extension and Farm Bureau in New York State, R-9 thru R-14